Guide to the Norman Baker student papers, [ca. 1952-1959]
Baker, Norman student papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Norman Baker student papers, [ca. 1952-1959]
14-22-3936
Norman Hodgson Baker 1931-
3 cubic feet.
Correspondence, course work, printed material, research material
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Notebooks from his graduate student courses at Cornell, with a few from the University of Minnesota.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Norman Hodgson Baker, Jr. (1931-2005) was one of the founders of the modern stellar pulsation theory, president of the Variable Star Commission 27 of the International Astronomical Union (1982-1985) and editor of Astronomical Journal. He received his B.A. from the University of Minnesota in 1952 and his Ph.D. in 1959 from Cornell, where he worked with Philip Morrison on radiation from particle interactions. After graduating from Cornell, he worked for two years at the Max-Planck-Institut für Physik und Astrophysik. He worked at Convair Science Research Laboratory in San Diego, and then at NASA Goddard Institute for Space Studies in New York, the Institute for Advanced Study at Princeton, the Astronomy Dept. at Yale, and the Physics Dept. at NYU. In 1965, he joined the faculty at Columbia, and retired in 2002. He died in 2005.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Notebooks from graduate student courses, covering topics on chemistry, zoology, physics, mathematics, languages, from Cornell University and the University of Minnesota. Also includes miscellaneous coursework.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Baker, Norman Hodgson,1931-; Cornell University.Dept. of Physics.; University of Minnesota.Dept. of Physics.
Subjects:
Physics--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- University of Minnesota, Theoretical Physics, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- University of Minnesota, Physics, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- University of Minnesota, Mathematics and Physics, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Physics 144, 146 and Math 107, 62
- University of Minnesota, x-ray spectra, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- University of Minnesota, physics coursework, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- University of Minnesota, physics lab manual, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- University of Minnesota, Mathematics 119-120, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- University of Minnesota, Mathematics 144, 145, 146, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- University of Minnesota, physics, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- University of Minnesota, Zoology, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- University of Minnesota, Chemistry classes, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- University of Minnesota, German, Misc. courses, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- University of Minnesota, Mathematics, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- University of Minnesota, Periodic Table of the Elements, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- M. 371 Shapiro?, 1955, Spring (Box 1, Folder 15)
- M. 505 Foundations of Analysis, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
- M. 506, Spring (Box 1, Folder 18)
- M. 721, 1955 Spring (Box 1, Folder 19)
- N. Baker notebook containing German, Physics, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- N. Baker German course work, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- N. Baker Russian course work, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- N. Baker Russian course work in Math binder, June-July (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Russian and other coursework in Math notebook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Unknown Coursework, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
- Unknown Physics Books, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
- Non-Turbulent Incompressible Flow in Channels with Breathing Walls, Post 1956 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- "Strange Particles" Lectures at Cornell University, 1957 Spring (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Maryland Academy of Sciences: Graphic Time Table of the Heavens, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Thesis requirements, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Annotated Drafts of Thesis, "Radiation from Particle Interaction which Create Current", 1959 February (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
- N. Baker, R. Kippenhahn, Draft of "The Pulsations of Models of Delta Cephei Stars II", Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- N. Baker, Works Submitted to NASA, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- "Advanced Class Physics" possible student coursework, February 9, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- N. Baker, The Convection Zone, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- N. Baker, WKZ in age-zero main sequence stars, July 12, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Notes and copy of "The Depth of the Outer Convection Zone in Main Sequence Stars", 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- "The Depth of the Outer Convection Zone in Main Sequence Stars", 1963 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Original of "The Depth of the Outer Convection Zone in Main Sequence Stars", 1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- N. Baker, Equil. Model Integrations, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Student course work for Astronomy 126b, May 1964 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Student course work from Stellar Atmospheres, January 1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Drafts and correspondence to The Astrophysical Journal concerning "The Pulsations of Models of Delta Cephei Stars II" N. Baker, April 16 1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- P. 117 Electricity and Magnetism, Tomboulian or Newhall, Fall (Box 3, Folder 1)
- P. 209 (no course listed); Parrott, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- P. 254 Electronic Properties of Solids and Liquids; Sack, 1954 Spring (Box 3, Folder 3)
- P. 380, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
- P. 476 I Electrodynamics; Morrison, 1953 Spring (Box 3, Folder 7)
- P. 476 II Electrodynamics; Morrison, 1953 Spring (Box 3, Folder 8)
- P. 477 Statistical Mechanics and Kinetic Theory; Morrison, 1954 Fall (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
- P. 485 Introductory Quantum Mechanics; Bethe and P. 486 Applications of Quantum Mechanics;Bethe, 1953 Fall and Spring (Box 3, Folder 11)
- P. 491 Advanced Quantum Mechanics, Salpeter, Fall (Box 3, Folder 12)
- P. 776 Nuclear and Particle Physics; Corson (Box 3, Folder 13)
- P. 775 Introductory Nuclear Physics; Corson, 1954-1955 Fall (Box 3, Folder 14)
- P. 786 Theory of High Energy Phenomena; (not listed), 1955 Spring (Box 3, Folder 15)
- P. 676, 1956 Spring (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Quantum Mechanics; Morrison, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Sommerfeld?, September 28 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- N. Baker, Unknown coursework, November 14 1952 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Unknown coursework, 1956 Spring (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Unknown coursework, Oct 17, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- N. Baker, unknown coursework, Fall (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Unknown coursework, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
- P. 475 Classical Mechanics, P. Morrison, Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)